Festival Accompanying Chapter
Part Eight
48 Hours
saa, wasuremashou sono mirai ga
Come, let us forget about the future...
Planning
Takeshi Oikawa
Akihiro Kawamura
Akihiro Yuasa
Original Work ・ Original Story/Supervision
Ryukishi07/07th Expansion
"Higurashi no Naku Koro ni"
"Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai"
mata chinurarete yuku nante
...ending up stained in blood again.
Series Composition
Toshifumi Kawase
Character Design
Overall Animation Supervisor
Kyuuta Sakai
Art Director
Chikako Shibata
Color Design
Shinji Matsumoto
namanurui kaze toguro wo maitara
If the soft wind coils up...
Camera Director
Masayuki Kawaguchi
Editing
Masahiro Matsumura
Music
Kenji Kawai
Sound Director
Hozumi Gouda
sore ga tabun aizu
...that is probably a sign.
nukedashitette
Break free.
Opening Theme
"Naraku no Hana"
(Flower in Hell)
Vocals
Lyrics
Composition
Arrangement
Eiko Shimamiya
Tomoyuki Nakazawa
Takeshi Ozaki
kanashisugiru unmei kara
From your heart-wrenching fate.
Music Producer
Music Production
Akira Yoshikawa
Frontier Works
anata wa naraku no hana ja nai
You are not a flower in hell.
Producers
Mika Nomura
Hiroyuki Oomori
Takeshi Okamura
sonna basho de sakanaide
Don't blossom in such a place.
Animation Producer
Animation Production
Kouji Iijima
Studio Deen
sakanaide
Don't blossom there.
karametorarete ikanaide
Don't get entangled.
oto mo naku tobikau toki no kakera
Fragments of time flutter about without a sound.
Kai
Hi
ni
ra
ku
Koro
gu
no
shi
Na
Kai
Production
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai Production Committee
Director
Chiaki Kon
Given everything proceeds without incident...
（鷹野(たかの)）万事つつがなく―
...First Lieutenant Tomitake will surely meet his pitiful demise tomorrow night.
明日の夜 富竹(とみたけ)二尉は
哀れな最期を遂げるでしょう
I see.
（野村(のむら)）そうですか　例の薬を…
Using that drug?
ええ　Ｈ173を使用します
Yes.
I will make use of H173.
To think that, in the process of developing a treatment for Hinamizawa Syndrome...
雛見沢(ひなみざわ)症候群の
治療薬を作る過程で―
まったく逆の効果を持つ薬が
できるとは
...we managed to produce a drug that has the exact opposite effect...
なんて皮肉なこと
Isn't it ironic?
His death will be the first move to bring suspicion upon the Irie Institution.
（野村）彼の死が―
入江(いりえ)機関に不審を抱かせる
最初の布石となります
We will take care of everything concerning this issue.
その辺りの工作は
こちらにすべてお任せください
Understood.
分かりました
Hello.
（受付）はい
エコノミーホテル興宮(おきのみや)でございます
Economy Hotel Okinomiya.
あの…　406号室の富竹を
お願いいたします
Excuse me...
I'd like to have Tomitake from room 406 on the line, please.
Please wait a minute.
（受付）少々お待ちください
I'm very sorry.
（受付）申し訳ございません
406号室のお客様は―
The guest in room 406 is currently out.
ただいま外出中です
そうですか　なら結構です
I see.
Never mind, then.
I'm such a fool.
バカね　ジロウさんと
何を話すと言うの？
What do I have to discuss with Jirou-san?
The words with which I discussed his murder have barely even left my mouth...
彼を殺す相談をしたその舌の根も
乾かないうちに…
I can no longer turn back.
もう戻ることはできない
"Operation 48 Hours."
（赤坂(あかさか)）48時間作戦…
I'm surprised.
驚きましたね
あんな子供たちが考えたなんて
To think those kids thought this up...
I think it has a good chance of success.
（入江）私は かなり
勝算があると思います
Indeed.
（赤坂）
ええ　連中に相当な揺さぶりを
かけられるでしょう
It could shake them up considerably.
So, when will the operation begin?
…で 作戦の発動は？
It depends on our discussion with Ooishi-san...
大石(おおいし)さんとの相談しだいですが
早いに越したことはないと思います
...but the sooner the better, I'd say.
Agreed.
（赤坂）同感です
The Yamainu have increased their security for the festival.
（入江）山狗(やまいぬ)は祭りに合わせて
警備レベルを上げています
So both the people on the streets as well as those in the shadows are making their preparations for tomorrow...
表も裏も 明日に向けて
同時に準備を進めている
…ということですか
[Saturday, June 18th]
It's going to be a festival tomorrow, in a lot of ways.
（入江）明日は いろいろな意味で
祭りになるでしょうね
How unusual to see you here!
珍しいですねえ　こんな所で
I just came to check out the preparations for the festival while taking my walk.
（鷹野）散歩がてら お祭りの
準備を見に寄っただけですわ
I hope it'll be sunny tomorrow.
明日は晴れるといいですね
雨で中止になったら気の毒です
It would be disappointing if it ended up cancelled due to rain.
It's the great festival people have been preparing for so extensively.
ここまで大々的に準備してきた
最高のお祭りですもの
It wouldn't get cancelled over something silly like rain.
雨ごときで
中止になるわけありませんわ
I suppose so.
そうですね　じゃあ…
See you.
By the way...
Would you happen to know where Jirou-san has gone?
（鷹野）ジロウさん―
どこに行かれているか
ご存じありません？
No.
（入江）いえ
I see.
そうですか…
I'm looking forward to tomorrow's festival.
明日の祭りが楽しみですね
Yes.
ええ　明日は楽しいお祭りに
なりますわよ
It'll be a lovely festival tomorrow.
Ooishi-san!
（魅音(みおん)）大石さん　どうでした？
How'd it go?
All right!
（圭一(けいいち)）よっしゃあ！
（歓声）
（魅音）話をまとめるの
大変だったでしょう？
It must've been tough to explain the situation to them.
（大石）いやあ それがね
あきれるくらい あっさり―
Well, about that...
Everyone boarded ship shockingly easily.
皆さん
船に乗ってくれちゃいまして
I can't pull back anymore.
もう後には引けません
Kuraudo Ooishi will stick with you until the very end!
この大石蔵人(くらうど)
最後まで突っ張りますよ
We can do it!
いける！　この作戦うまくいくぜ
This operation is gonna work!
Things have gotten interesting!
（沙都子(さとこ)）
何だか楽しくなってきましたわね
Rika.
（羽入(はにゅう)）梨花(りか)
（梨花）あ…
Having so many allies means we can be this confident.
（羽入）味方が多いということは
こんなにも心強いことなのです
Until only a few days ago...
（梨花）ほんの数日前までは
運命に屈しかけていたというのにね
...we were on the verge of giving in to fate.
We might really be able to throw it around this time.
今度こそ 本当に
ひっくり返せるかもしれないわね
Rika!
梨花！　そんな弱い気持ちでは
ダメなのです
We won't win with such a half-hearted attitude!
You're right.
そうね　ひっくり返せる“かも”
じゃない
We not just 'might' be able to throw it around.
We will.
ひっくり返す　勝つ
We will win!
We will defeat fate!
私たちは運命を打ち破る
Tonight...
（圭一）今夜には 梨花ちゃんが
姿を消してから48時間が成立する
...forty-eight hours will have passed since Rika-chan's disappearance.
Now it comes to timing.
あとはタイミングですわね
A surprise attack should naturally be made at night!
（圭一）奇襲なら夜だろう
You're talking about times in which electricity didn't exist.
（魅音）そりゃ
電気がなかった時代の話だよ
There is a far more appropriate time for this.
もっと最適な時間がある
A more suitable time?
より適した時間？
I see.
なるほど　夜明け前なのです
Before dawn.
People definitely hate being woken up before dawn more than at midnight.
確かに深夜よりも明け方に
起こされるほうがイヤですねえ
And when they're still half asleep, they won't be able to make sharp judgments.
寝ぼけているところでは
正確な判断もできないでしょう
A surprise attack at dawn, huh?
夜明けの奇襲か
く～っ！　何だよ それ
That's awesome!
男として一度は
やってみたいシチュエーション
A situation every man wants to experience once!
燃えてきた！
I'm fired up!
よーし！
部長 園崎(そのざき)魅音の名において―
All right!
In the name of Club President Mion Sonozaki...
48時間作戦の発動を命ず！
...I will order the initiation of Operation 48 Hours!
The operation will commence tomorrow, June 19th, at 4 a.m.!
決行は明日 ６月19日 午前４時！
Oh crap!
（圭一）やっべえ
俺 マジでアドレナリン全開！
My adrenaline is rushing at full force!
（魅音）アハハッ…
Who will win, Takano or us?
（梨花）勝つのは鷹野か私たちか
The time has finally come.
さあ　今こそ その時は来た
Let's open up the door of June 19th, 1983!
開こう　昭和58年６月19日の扉を
Yes.
はい　鷹野です
This is Takano.
What the hell is going on!?
（小此木(おこのぎ)）一体どうなってるんだ!?
正確に情報を伝えんか！
Bring me the exact situation!
Surveillance squad!
（隊員）
監視班　目標宅の状況を知らせろ
What's the situation at the target house?
Is there no one at Okinomiya Police Station?
興宮署には誰もいないのか？
白鷺(しらさぎ)　現在位置は…　ん？
Egret, what's your current location!?
（隊員）
鴉(からす)と連絡が取れました
We managed to contact Skylark.
Very sorry to have woken you up.
お休みのところ
申し訳ありませんねえ
What's our status?
（鷹野）状況を
はっ…　午前４時15分
興宮署内で身元不明死体が―
Yes.
At 4:15 a.m...
...we received word that an unidentifiable corpse at Okinomiya Police Station has been confirmed to be our target.
目標であると確認されたとの情報が
入りました
That can't be!
そんなわけないでしょう！
梨花は風邪で寝込んでいるはずよ
Rika should be in bed with a cold!
（小此木）しかも報告によれば
死後48時間以上 経過しているとか
What's more, according to reports...
...forty-eight hours have already passed since her death.
That's impossible!
そんなこと あり得ない
Then what about the villagers?
だったら村人は どうなの？
誰か発症した？
Did anyone fall ill?
その様子はありません
There are no signs of it.
Isn't that strange!?
（鷹野）おかしいじゃない！
Terminal symptoms should already appear as soon as thirty-six hours after the event.
早ければ36時間の段階で
末期症状が出ているはずよ
B-But...
し… しかし
興宮署の諜報(ちょうほう)員によれば―
...according to our agents within Okinomiya Station, this information is very reliable.
かなり確実性の高い情報だと…
Don't be ridiculous!
（鷹野）ふざけないで！
あなた 雛見沢症候群を忘れたの？
Did you forget about Hinamizawa Syndrome!?
If the Queen Carrier dies...
女王感染者が死ねば
48時間で村人全員が末期発症する
...the entire village will develop the terminal symptoms within forty-eight hours!
これは絶対確実！
疑いようのない真実よ
This is absolutely certain!
The undeniable truth!
If the villagers aren't showing the symptoms...
村人が発症していなければ
古手(ふるで)梨花は死んでいない
...then Rika Furude is not dead!
そうでしょう!?
Isn't that so!?
But...
ですが…
What about Rika Furude's surveillance?
（鷹野）古手梨花の監視は？
According to reports...
（隊員）報告によれば
家を出た者は１人もおりません
...not a single person has left the house.
The target is still inside.
目標は依然 屋内です
Our surveillance is flawless.
（小此木）監視体制は完璧です
Director Irie confirmed her presence inside the house as well.
中にいたことも
入江所長が確認なさってます
（隊員）
はい　分かりました
少々お待ちください
Then how do you explain this!?
なら どういうことよ!?
（小此木）分かりません
I do not know.
（隊員）三佐　東京の野村様より
お電話が入っております
Major.
A phone call from Ms. Nomura from Tokyo.
あっ…　もう嗅ぎつけたの!?
They got wind of it already!?
いいわ　私の部屋に回して
Fine.
Put it through to my room.
Have the body at Okinomiya Police Station investigated immediately!
すぐ興宮署の死体を調べさせない
We are currently in extreme disorder.
（小此木）現在は非常に困難です
出勤時間になれば協力者も…
Once it is time for work, our cooperators will...
This is an emergency!
緊急事態よ　急がせなさい！
Have them make haste!
[Identification Lab]
Okay, there's no way back anymore!
（鑑識）
さあて もう後戻りはでけんぞい
Don't worry!
（熊谷(くまがい)）任してください　たとえ
死体になっても 誰も通しません
They would have to go over my dead body to pass through!
そんときゃあ わしが見てやるぞい
I'll look after you when that happens!
（鑑識）来おったな
Here it comes.
Where did it come from?
どこからですか？
Inspector Ootaka from Prefectural HQ.
（刑事）県警本部 大高(おおたか)警部です
ほう　大高君か　へえ…
Ootaka-kun, huh?
I see.
（大石）なるほど
あのインテリ坊やがスパイとはねえ
So that brainiac was a spy...
Even though he chose organized crime investigation, he was just an organizational dog himself.
組織捜査だのと偉ぶっていても
しょせんは組織の犬ですか　フフッ
Looks like the conversation is over.
通話が終わったようです
Hello?
もしもし？　おっとと…　大丈夫
私ですよ　いかがでした？
Oh, oh, don't worry, it's me.
How did it go?
アッハハッ！
青二才が粋がりおってからに
The rookie was acting like a smart ass, so I told him off good!
鼻で あしらってやったわ
（大石）お見事です
Well done.
わしも ますます
面白くなってきたぞい
I'm starting to enjoy this even more now.
That phone call snapped me out of my drowsiness.
今の電話で眠気が吹っ飛んだわ
やはり いるな
お前の言う怪しげな連中が―
They're around after all.
I can feel the suspicous people you've been talking about crawling out one by one.
ぞろぞろと
はい出してくるのを感じるぞ
さあて 面白くなってきましたよ
Now things have gotten interesting.
“鬼さん こちら
手の鳴るほうへ”ってね
"Here, Mr. Demon. Come out, come out, wherever you are."
Everyone is in disarray...
どいつも こいつも動揺して
何だって言うのよ!?
What the hell are they doing!?
Rika died?
梨花が死んだ？　48時間も前に？
村人は平穏無事？
Over forty-eight hours ago?
And the villagers are safe and sound?
フン…　そんなこと
あるわけないじゃない！
That's utterly ridiculous!
It's false information.
デマよ　デマに決まってる！
そうじゃなければ…
It's obviously false information!
If it weren't...
Not yet.
まだよ　まだ負けるものですか！
I'm not about to lose yet!
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni
Kai
Yeah, got it.
ああ 分かった
Once you learn more of the situation at Okinomiya Station, contact me and the Major.
興宮署のほうは分かりしだい
俺と三佐に連絡しろ
Did you manage to confirm the target's presence in the house?
目標の在宅は確認できたか？
We don't know if it's the target...
（隊員）目標かどうかは
分かりませんが―
...but there is no doubt someone is inside the house.
家屋内に誰かいるのは
間違いありません
バカ野郎！　目標かどうか
分からなけりゃ意味ねえだろうが！
You stupid moron!
What's the point if you don't know whether it's the target or not!?
Damnit!
クソッ！　三佐の許可さえあれば
突入という手段も取れるのに…
If only we had the Major's approval...
...we could infiltrate the house!
Captain.
（隊員）隊長
今日は境内で祭りがある日です
There is a festival held at the shrine grounds today.
We should be able to observe...
監視はできるでしょうが 突入は
おそらく本日深夜まで不可能かと…
...but infiltration will likely be impossible until midnight.
チッ　うまいタイミングだ
Perfect timing.
No...
いや　うますぎねえか？　こいつは
Isn't this a little too perfect?
Don't tell me...
まさか…
This is an enemy attack!
これは敵の攻撃だ　こちらが
動く前に先手を取られたんだ！
They took the initiative before we made our move!
くっ…　相手は何者だ？
Who are we up against?
It has to be someone with military know-how and expertise in information warfare...
戦略に精通し情報戦にも たけて…
ん…　雲雀(ひばり)を集めろ！　大至急だ！
Gather up Skylark!
On the double!
（富竹）興宮署の？
At Okinomiya Police Station?
Yes.
（調査部員）
ええ　未確認ですが―
It is unconfirmed, but a number of employees of the Identification Department attested this.
“鑑識課職員 複数が
証言している”と
We initially suspected it to be misinformation as well...
こちらも誤報を疑いましたが
情報の精度は極めて高く―
...but the accuracy of this information is exceedingly high...
女王感染者の死は
ほぼ間違いありません
...so there is little doubt that the Queen Carrier has died.
B-But...
（富竹）えっ しかし…
（富竹）あっ…　興宮署は
大石さんのテリトリーじゃないか
Okinomiya Police Station is Ooishi-san's territory.
I see!
そうか
Hello?
（調査部員）もしもし　富竹二尉？
First Lieutenant Tomitake?
ああ 失礼　現状を考えるに
入江機関への緊急査察―
Excuse me.
Considering the current situation...
...I propose an emergency investigation of the Irie Institution, as well as putting the Banken unit on standby.
それと番犬部隊への待機命令を
進言します
Roger that.
（調査部員）
了解しました　それと先ほど―
Also, it seems the Yamainu were urgently mobilized earlier.
山狗に緊急招集が
かけられた模様です
The Yamainu!?
（富竹）山狗が!?
（小此木）チッ　もぬけの殻かよ
Completely empty!?
First Lieutenant Tomitake enjoyed wild bird photography and walking.
（隊員）富竹二尉には
野鳥撮影と散策の趣味がありました
He might have gone out in the early morning...
もしかすると早朝から…
いや 違うな
たぶん 奴は襲撃を予見し―
No, that's not it.
He probably predicted our raid...
ずっと前に宿を変えていたんだ
（隊員）では…
....and changed his lodging a long time ago.
Then...
Make an emergency call to the Major.
三佐に緊急連絡しろ
ちくしょう…
こちらの作戦が漏れているぞ！
Goddamnit.
Our operation is being leaked!
Nice work.
お疲れさんです
今度は うちのハナタレ署長じゃわ
This time it was our snot-nosed chief.
どんどん手ごわくなってくるが―
They're gradually getting more tough, but hey...
なあに
しょせん わしの敵じゃないわな
...they're no match for me, anyway.
フウ…
I wonder how Ootaka will make his appearance.
大高の奴 どう出ますかね？
まあ 彼の性分なら―
Well, considering his nature, he'll come marching in wielding his authority.
乗り込んでくるでしょうね
権力 振りかざして
Please take care of that.
（鑑識）そっちは頼むぞ
水際撃退といきましょうかねえ
I suppose I should fight him off at the waterside.
フウ…
Kuma-chan, I leave the castle keep to you.
熊ちゃんは本丸を頼みます
（熊谷）了解っす
Got it.
What should we do, Captain?
（隊員）どうしますか？　隊長
He hasn't gone far off.
遠くには行っていない　俺たちの
動きを探ってるはずだからな
He's supposed to be watching our moves, after all.
Contact Raven in Tokyo.
東京の鴉に連絡を取れ
Have them look into the phone number of whoever the Investigation Bureau is regularly in contact with.
調査部が定期連絡している相手先の
電話番号を調べさせるんだ
鹿骨(ししぼね)市内ならビンゴだ
If it's a number within Shishibone, it's bingo.
Roger.
（隊員）了解しました
（隊員）こちら雲雀４
鴉と連絡を取りたい　大至急だ
This is Skylark Four.
I'd like to get into contact with Raven.
Immediately.
The fact that the Investigation Bureau is acting means they are suspicious of us.
（小此木）調査部が動いていれば
俺たちを疑っているってことだ
But it isn't checkmate yet.
だが まだチェックメイトじゃない
If we can confirm the body at Okinomiya Station isn't the target...
興宮署の死体が
目標じゃないと確認されれば…
I contacted Raven.
鴉と連絡が取れました
It seems they'll be able to figure out the phone number.
電話番号だけなら
何とか調べられるそうです
How long will it take?
どれぐらい かかる？
（隊員）
ほんの数時間ほどだそうです
Only a few hours, it seems.
チッ　“ほんの”と来たもんか
"Only" a few hours!?
可能な限り急がせろ！
Make them do it as fast as possible!
This is Phoenix One.
こちら鳳(おおとり)１　どうした？
What's wrong?
The Banken received the standby order.
（隊員）
番犬に待機命令が出ました
任務は示されていないとのことです
It doesn't appear they have been assigned a task.
Which means they could still be called back.
…てことは
まだ取り消せるわけだな
時間は あるのか
We still have time.
（隊員）あ…　続報です
An update.
The head of the Investigation Bureau is making a call to the Chief of Staff.
（隊員）
調査部長が幕僚長の自宅に
電話しています　内容は不明
Subject matter unknown.
Understood.
分かった　引き続き監視しろ
Keep monitoring.
番犬を動かすために
上が調整に入ったってことか
So the higher-ups have begun preparations for the mobilization of the Banken...
チッ　まずいな
This is bad.
Good morning, Ootaka-kun.
おはようございます　大高君
Didn't I tell you not to address me with "kun"?
（大高）
私を“君”呼ばわりしないよう
言ったでしょう
もう立場が違うんです
I'm your superior now.
まあまあ そう言わずに大高君
Oh come on, don't be like that, Ootaka-kun.
I have some urgent business to attend to today...
（大高）
今日は急ぎの用事がありますので
失礼させていただきます
...so if you'll excuse me.
Your territory is Prefectural HQ, not Okinomiya Station.
あんたのシマは県警本部であって
興宮じゃあない
引き上げてもらいましょう
Please leave.
（大高）私たちは
重大な事件の捜査中だぞ
We are in the middle of investigating a very important case.
ほう？
秘匿捜査中の事件に―
There is a possibility the unidentified body here is connected to an incident we are secretly investigating.
ここの身元不明死体が
関連している可能性がある
一体 何の事件です？　そりゃあ
And what incident would that be?
Nothing someone like you have to know about.
君ごときが知らなくていいことだ
いいから そこをどきたまえ！
Now get out of my way.
んっ!?
（大石）ここは通しませんよ
I won't let you pass here.
I have two thousand Hinamizawan lives on my shoulders.
私はねえ 雛見沢2000人の命を
しょってるんです
You know what I mean by that, don't you?
分かりますよね？　この意味
（大高）
ん…　何の話か さっぱりだ
I have no clue what you're talking about.
あんたの飼い主は
恐ろしいことをたくらんでいる
Your master is plotting something horrifying.
A despicable conspiracy that will bring misfortune to thousands of people!
何千人もの人が不幸になる
とんでもない陰謀だ
こ… これは捜査妨害…
Y-You're obstructing our investigation!
No, you're obstructing an officer from performing his duty!
いや 公務執行妨害だ
逮捕するぞ！
I will arrest you!
なら あんたは大量殺人の共犯だ！
In that case you are guilty of accessory to mass murder!
A-Arrest him!
こ… こいつを逮捕しろ！
（刑事たち）あっ…
（大高）どうした？　何をしてる！
What the heck are you waiting for!?
How about doing it yourself?
自分で来たら どうです？
青二才が
You damn rookie.
（大石）ええい　てやっ！
（大高）あ… ああ…
フウ…　粋がるなよ
刑事魂もねえくせに
Don't get cocky.
You don't have any police spirit.
くっ…　よくも こんなマネを…
How dare you...
私の依頼主が黙っちゃいないぞ！
My client won't keep quiet about this!
And who is that?
（大石）
誰だい？　ぜひ聞きたいですねえ
I'd sure love to know.
フッ…　いいでしょう
あなたの大の苦手 園崎議員ですよ
Very well.
It's the man you dread so much, Councilor Sonozaki!
（大石）ああ～　あの怖い人ねえ
あっ 確かに苦手ですね
That scary person.
Yeah, I sure don't like him.
あっ そりゃ大変だあ
Oh boy, whatever will I do.
（大高）フフフ　そうでしょうとも
What will you do indeed?
園崎議員とは懇意にしてましてねえ
I happen to be on cordial terms with Councilor Sonozaki.
あなたが邪魔をするなら
その旨 伝えますよ
If you are going to obstruct me, I will inform him to that effect.
あっ どうも
またスピード違反ですか？
Oh hello, were you fined for speeding again?
でしたら ８番の窓口に…
If so, please proceed to window number eight.
My car's engine stalls at the legal speed.
（茜(あかね)）あたしの車は
法定速度じゃエンストしちまうのさ
（茜）アッハハハ…
（大高）ん？
（茜）ねえ お前さん
Hey, you.
本当に園崎議員に頼まれたんだね？
秘書とかじゃなくて
So you were really asked by Councilor Sonozaki, right?
Not by his secretary or anything?
なっ…　もちろんですよ
Naturally.
園崎議員とは
直接お電話を頂く関係でしてね
Me and Councilor Sonozaki phone call each other directly.
（三郎(さぶろう)）お前 誰じゃ？
Who the hell are you?
できすぎなシチュエーションで
笑うしかないですなあ
Can't help but laugh at this scene taken right out of a comedy.
H-How rude!
し… 失礼な　誰だ あんたら!?
Who are you two!?
Oh, can't you tell?
あら　分からないのかい？
お前とは懇意なんじゃろう？
わしは…
Aren't I on cordial terms with you?
園崎茜さんと園崎三郎さんですよ
These are Akane and Saburou Sonozaki.
“県議の園崎先生”と言えば
分かりますかな？
Or would it be more clear if I called him "Mr. Sonozaki of the Prefectural Assembly"?
I will confirm this once more.
（鷹野）もう一度 確認します
昨日の時点で
入江所長は女王感染者が―
Yesterday...
...you confirmed that the Queen Carrier was at home, right?
在宅しているのを
確認したんですね？
What's to confirm?
“確認した？”って…
夏風邪を引いたというので
見に行っただけですよ
She caught a summer cold, so I just went to check her up.
She was almost completely back to her old self...
まっ だいぶ
元気になりましたから―
うまく抜け出して
遊びに出かけたかもしれませんが
...so she might have slipped out and went to play somewhere.
Is that possible?
（鷹野）そんなこと あり得るの？
（隊員）あり得ません
Impossible.
監視班は誰１人として
出ていないと報告しています
The surveillance squad reported not a single person has left the house.
（鷹野）
昨日 入江所長は在宅を確認した
Yesterday...
...Director Irie confirmed she was at home.
山狗は誰も出ていないという
And the Yamainu say no one left the house.
なら どうして
興宮署で梨花の死体が出るの!?
Then how does Rika's body turn up at Okinomiya Police Station!?
（隊員）
三佐　東京の野村様からです
Major.
Phone from Ms. Nomura from Tokyo.
しばらく待てと言っているのに
I told her to wait a moment...
はい
Yes.
ですから
何度もお伝えしているように―
As I keep telling you...
現在 情報を確認中で…
...we are still sorting out the situation...
My clients are getting agitated.
（野村）クライアントたちに
動揺が広がっています
At this rate, the plan itself will be swept under the carpet.
このままでは計画自体が
なかったことになりますよ？
待ってください！
Please wait!
（野村）それは すなわち
あなたの祖父の論文が―
In other words...
...the thesis of your grandfather will be branded as utter nonsense.
世迷(よま)い言だったと
烙印(らくいん)を押されることですよ？
What folly!
“なんてバカバカしい
空想 妄想にも程がある”
There is a limit to delusion!
“高野(たかの)一二三(ひふみ)と鷹野三四(みよ)って
何なのかしら？”
What the heck were Hifumi and Miyo Takano on?
アッハッハッハッハッ
…ということになりますよ
よろしいですか？
That's what's going to happen.
Understand?
Yes...
It's from Raven.
鴉からです
（小此木）ん？
The phone number that has been regularly contacting the Investigation Bureau has been identified.
調査部の定期連絡先の
電話番号を特定しました
来たか！
Finally!
電話番号は鹿骨市内です
The phone number is within Shishibone.
It has to be Tomitake!
富竹だ　間違いない！
雲雀を直ちに急行させろ！
Have Skylark move out immediately!
Found it.
特定しました
Hotel Moderato in the center of the city.
市内“ホテル モデラート”
部屋番号は不明
Room number unkown.
（小此木）鳳１より雲雀１へ
Phoenix One to Skylark Ten.
奴は用心してるぞ
抜かるんじゃねえ！
He's on his guard.
Don't let him slip away.
やっと見つけたのね　裏切り者を
I finally found him.
The traitor.
ウソつきには
きつく お仕置きしなきゃ
Liars have to be harshly punished.
はっ…　ジロウさんだけじゃなく
他にもウソつきがいたとしたら…
What if it isn't just Jirou-san...
...but more liars besides him exist?
裏切り者が１人じゃなかったら…
What if there was more than one traitor...
入江所長に監視を付けなさい！
Keep Director Irie under surveillance!
（隊員）は？　所長にですか？
The Director?
そうよ
Yes.
絶対に目を離さないで！
Do not let him out of your sight!
Cast
Keiichi Maebara
Rena Ryuuguu
Mion Sonozaki
Satoko Houjou
Rika Furude
Hanyuu
Souichiro Hoshi
Mai Nakahara
Satsuki Yukino
Mika Kanai
Yukari Tamura
Yui Horie
anata no nakigara ni tsuchi wo kakeru
I cover your corpse with soil...
Cast
Miyo Takano
Miki Itou
Cast
Jirou Tomitake
Kuraudo Ooishi
Kyousuke Irie
Katsuya Kumagai
Mamoru Akasaka
Okonogi
Woman
Forensics Officer
Akane Sonozaki
Saburou Sonozaki
Ootaka
Yamainu
Tohru Ookawa
Chafuurin
Toshihiko Seki
Takuo Kawamura
Daisuke Ono
Jurota Kosugi
Rie Tanaka
Eiji Maruyama
Kikuko Inoue
Kousei Hirota
Kouji Ishii
Nobuyuki Kobushi
Satoshi Tsuruoka
Daisuke Matsuoka
Katsuhiro Oota
Gen Nakano
sore ga kinjirareteita toshitemo
...even though that may have been forbidden.
junsui na manazashi no kairaku ni wa
There was a temptation you could not hide...
kakushikirenai yuuwaku ga atta
...in your pure, blissful eyes.
doushite tsumi ga aru no darou
Why does sin exist?
Ending Theme
"Taishou a"
(Target a)
Vocals
Lyrics
Composition/
Arrangement
doushite batsu ga aru no darou
Why does punishment exist?
hone no saki wa amari ni mo shiroku
That blindingly white tip of the bone...
mugen ni tsuzuku yami wo sasotta
...invited the infinite darkness.
Scenario
Masashi Suzuki
Storyboards
Episode Direction
Akira Iwanaga
Yuuji Seki
nani mo kamo ga azayaka ni miete
I can see everything clearly now.
Animation Supervisor
Hiromichi Mizukawa
sugu ni kieteshimau
It will soon vanish.
Animation Production
Studio Deen
Production
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai Production Committee
© 2007 Ryukishi07/Hinamizawa Three Great Houses
（ドアが開く音）
（隊員）いたか？
Is he here?
あっ…
（隊員）空き室だ　次！
It's a vacant room!
Next!
There he is!
（隊員）いたぞ！
He's on his own!
（隊員）
相手は１人だ　かかれ！
Get him!
（隊員たち）やあー！
（富竹）くっ…
Oryou's Ohagi Song!
（梨花･羽入）お魎(りょう)の おはぎ歌～
Knead, knead the bean paste...
（梨花）あんこを こねこね
（羽入）真ん丸く～
...and roll into a ball!
Tuck in some azuki beans...
（梨花）小豆に包んで
（羽入）真ん丸く～
...and roll into a ball!
（梨花）愛情 込めて
Pour in affection...
（羽入）真ん丸く～
...and roll into a ball!
（梨花）そして最後に隠し味
And finally the secret ingredient!
Look forward to eating it!
（羽入）あとは 食べてのお楽しみ！
Next time, the Festival Accompanying Chapter, Part Nine.
（羽入）次回　祭囃し編 其の九
「攻防」
"Attack and Defense."
Watch!
（羽入）見るのです～！
（梨花）あなたも食べてみる？
Do you want to have a taste?
Higurashi no Naku Koro ni Kai
Next time
Festival Accompanying Chapter
Part Nine
Attack and Defense